Alrighty, good morning everyone. I hope
you had a restful uh new year. I am
proud to see everyone back here and
happy to see familiar faces as well as
some new ones. Um I call this meeting of
the medical psilocyment advisory board
to order. Um and then do we have a draft
agenda? I know we were just doing um
kind of an overview from the department
and then checking in on committees, but
um do we have a finalized one?
>> Yes, we do. Uh Ian, I am uh pulling it
up now. It's just taking it a moment.
>> You should all start to see. Can people
see the um PowerPoint now?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, great. And here is the agenda and
I will be putting that in the chat as
well.
>> Perfect. All right. And then if we have
a board member to move to adopt the
agenda.
>> I move to adopt the agenda.
>> Any second?
>> I second that.
>> Perfect. Um all right. We can go ahead
and adopt the agenda if there are no
objections. So let's go ahead and just
get this um started with an update from
the program.
Hey, good morning everybody. Uh thank
you all for being here, especially our
board members. We really appreciate it.
Um it has been a very busy couple of
weeks. Uh the committees have been
meeting um and uh it has been really
great to hear it. I know uh there'll be
more information and updates from the
committees, but uh it's just been really
great and uh just hearing all of the
comments and the commentary has been
really good. I do want to say we have
had one issue with regard to some of the
meeting minutes and some of you may have
heard this as we were before the meeting
actually had officially started but what
we're having is we're having a few
people who are sending us lots and lots
of documents and no context with the
documents and some of them are things
for example just rules and regulations
from Colorado or from Oregon without
context in them and that means um while
we have to put items like that then do
go as part of the record those are
already documents and items that are
available elsewhere. And so what we are
going to be asking and doing is stating
that if you're referencing a document
that lives somewhere else, what we just
need is we just need the hyperlink to
it. Um because otherwise our concern is
people are going to see in these records
and the documents hundreds of pages and
instead of actually looking and seeing
the analysis recommendations thoughts
people are going to simply just say I'm
not going to bother reading this because
there are hundreds of pages. And so if
you're referencing a particular aspect
of, for example, a uh an area from uh an
area of the regulations from Colorado,
actually just site that particular
section of the regulations, that
particular point, and uh include the
hyperlink so people can go to it
themselves and put in what you're trying
to talk about and what your point is
rather than just simply sending in pages
and pages of uh of regulations. Um, and
other than that, we continue to move
forward in supporting the board with
regard to the meetings and we're
continuing to get things posted. The
other update with regard to that is
please do remember whenever and this is
for everybody and the public and glad to
see so many people are here right now
that as we do post items because they do
have to be reviewed for things. For
example, in one committee meeting there
was a cuss word that was said. So our
team that actually reviews and goes
through had to mute that particular and
bleep that particular section. So um
those sort of things have to be reviewed
before we can put them out there because
once we do these are available to the
public including individuals who are
underage. So it is also our reminder of
please watch what's being said. Um, and
just uh some of the other things that
have occurred in the past is some people
have given us feedback that they'd like
to see everyone. And there are a couple
of reasons why we don't have cameras on
for the uh the participants in it
outside of the board members and some of
the program staff. And the reason for
that is actually twofold. One is because
some people because we have so many
people joining in on the meetings. Some
people were experiencing problems due to
the load of for their internet and their
internet connection and especially in
areas where their internet was so not so
great. They would keep dropping out and
having to join back on in. So we do that
to try to help that stability with
regard to that. The other reason for it
is because there occasionally have been
things that were inappropriate in the
backgrounds and so we have to minimize
that and make sure that that doesn't
happen during meetings and while we are
sure that it is unintentional we do have
to make sure again that the videos that
are done the recordings of these
meetings can be available to the public
and so we want to be able to ensure
that. So those are the two reasons for
that and again uh we would hope that in
the future we'd be able to at least have
people uh visually in some of the
meetings um at least for a brief bit and
we are looking into some of those
potential solutions. Um but other than
that um the program is just moving
forward. Um we have been um uh
interviewing for the two other program
positions. So, as many people know right
now and he's on this call, our program
manager for medical psilocybin is Jorge
Gonzalez. Um, and uh, and again, he is
with us here. And we have two other
positions that had been allocated to the
program, one is a compliance officer,
one is an associate um, uh,
environmental scientist. And we have
been working on those interviews with
those staff members. there was quite a
lot of interest and so quite a few
interviews and um we will hopefully be
moving forward with those positions here
soon. So I'm hopeful that by the next
meeting or at worst case the meeting
after that there will be some additional
information regarding those positions
that will add a lot of capacity for the
program. Um, as many people know, right
now technically the only individual who
is actually dedicated to the program is
the program manager, Jorge. Um, which
doesn't mean, by the way, I'm not
dedicated to the program and that other
staff members aren't helping. It just
his position is the only current
full-time medical psilocybin position.
So, we will essentially triple our staff
here within this, let's say, the next 3
weeks to a month. And that is great news
all around and we will be able to
provide additional support and some
other items with it. Um so thank you
everybody. Um and other than that it's
really right now we're in that
administrative time of getting
everything set up to be supportive and
so um we really appreciate it and uh
again forgive us as we make mistakes
because we are only human. We will do
our best to rectify if there when there
are mistakes and as we get things moving
forward. So, thank you.
>> Thank you, Dominic, um, for that update
from the program. Yeah, like you said,
we're just kind of washing out all of
the, you know, little administrative
tasks that are part of developing a
program like this. And with the
additional support, we should be able to
um, fully flush out this program. Um, so
what I wanted to go ahead and get into
now was a summary or just kind of
updates from the committees. I'll go
ahead and go with um propagation first
and just see what are any updates. Have
you guys um you know adopted governance
meeting for the first time? Just kind of
a summary of where you guys are at. So
I'll turn over to Chris.
>> Thank you. Uh yes, we had our first
propagation meeting and it was uh I
think it went very well. We had a lot of
um a lot of engagement within the
meeting. we adopted our bylaws and we
just kind of began talking about where
we're going with it. Um, one question I
do have for the rest of the board is it
didn't explicitly say this in in the um
the summary of the duties, but I didn't
see it anywhere else either. So, I'm
kind of assuming that uh the propagation
committee is going to take over, you
know, cultivation
through distribution.
Um, and so we talked about that and all
the work that needs to be done and we
have our next meeting set for next
Wednesday where we're going to start
talking about cultivation. Um,
but if I'm wrong on our need to
um address distribution as well in that
um in that committee, please let me
know. Um but I I feel like it's the
logical place for it to kind of sit.
>> Yeah. Um yeah, that's actually perfect.
So I would imagine the propagation
committee taking over kind of
it would see everything the medicine
sees before the patient. Um so if they
transportation to the facility
everything but you know preparation
administration integration involving the
mushrooms would be under um that
cultivation and manufacturing in that
section. So um I believe your
interpretation is correct. Uh I will go
ahead and now go to equity access and
cultural considerations with Desba.
>> Hi. Um yes, so we did have a couple of
meetings. I did do a first morning
meeting um for for those who are
available during the day, but then I
also had another meeting um at night. Um
I think I'm probably going to go back
and forth between morning and um evening
meetings for some people because I know
it's not easy for everyone to get away
during the day um and easier for some
people to get away at night. But I don't
know. I'd like some input on that from
the public. Um but we had some meetings
um two of them and we did not do any
governance agreements. This was more of
a listening session to see um an open um
yeah just to listen to what general
public kind of had concerns of where
like the the uh temperature of concerns.
A lot of it was of course with the
equity and access and cultural
considerations was cost for both um
facilitators licensing what that looks
like. Um also for treatments um a lot of
so far when I say a lot I mean there's
just been a couple of people who have
mentioned you know rural access
tellaalth what that looks like um and
um but then of course um
what that looks like when it comes to h
how equity access and cultural
considerations looks like in the
framework of all the other committees.
That's one of the things that I
definitely want to kind of focus on is
where does that intersect all the other
committees, all the other um areas that
we need to have concern because I see
that and also in some of the other
presentations is the affordability and
the access is also education. What is
the education and outreach look like? Um
there was a lot of outside input which
is not a problem. We have people from
Oregon talking about them having their
own um programs and business and how
they were affected in Oregon. Um haven't
really heard anything necessarily from
Colorado. I've heard some concerns from
Arizona. Again, all of this input is
interesting to hear, especially since
Oregon has already established their
program. Um but we definitely of course
need to have all of that consideration
for New Mexico. Um
let's see there's also some other things
in um the meeting notes. One point for
the sake of the public and then also for
the board is that we did discuss um how
the regulations are going to possibly
intersect affect um tribal governance
when it comes to the 24 tribes. So, we
do have a tribal liaison um within the
department of health who um I can
Dominic can speak a little bit more to
that if you would like to. Um but my
understanding is that we are going to
wait because there is a legislative
session that will be happening next
week. And so we're going to wait until
we can get some more meetings set up um
and utilizing that liaison to then reach
out to the tribes and have more
formalized meetings and listening
sessions for what the tribes um
particularly need. And again also for
the sake of the public because New
Mexico has represents 24 federally
recognized tribes which include the
Apache um tribes, Navajo Nation and the
PBLO. um they just recently changed
their governance which they do every
year. So we're waiting for that kind of
catch-up period to establish what the
governors um we who they are, what's
going on, their change um um in
governance and leadership right now. So
it's not as if it's not on um the radar,
but we're going to wait for a little bit
to get that going uh specifically.
And um yeah, I would say that that's
pretty much all for right now. Um and
then for the next meeting that I do
believe is the 21st of next week before
we have um some more meetings and that
one will be establishing more
agreements. That one will be more
formalized. Um and I Yeah. So that's all
for right now.
>> Thank you so much. I appreciate the
update. Um the training and education
committee has not met yet, but they will
be meeting on the 23rd. Uh how about an
update from the end of life care
committee with Larry Leman?
>> Oh, and just real quick, um just to
clarify, the um it's the 20th for the
next um equity and access meeting.
>> Okay. Yeah, the 20th. And then but
training and education is on the 23rd.
No.
>> Yes. Yes, it is.
>> Yes.
>> Okay, perfect. Um yeah, so that one's
going to be on the 23rd. So please be
sure to check in that one. Um very
important stuff with how uh we're going
to pick who can, you know, prescribe and
who can recommend these treatments. So
it is very important. I will go ahead
and turn over again to Larry Leman.
Are you able to see my screen share?
>> Yes.
>> Great. Okay. For some reason, it's
saying my mic is disabled, but clearly
it's not. So, good. Anyway, good morning
everybody. Good to be meeting with
people again. Um we had one meeting at
the end of life uh committee uh we went
through we all approved bylaws we um
focused on scopes and responsibilities
and I was just going to go over that um
a few slides to kind of share what we
what we focused on and what we saw as
the direction that we wanted to head in.
We also had a good amount of time for
public uh public um comment and such and
we had a good I think we had close to 50
people on the meeting. It was a big
crowd. So I thought it went well well.
So these from we started with six and
added a seventh scope and responsibility
and gave it some input for each of us.
One of them is establishing the
definition of the scope for end of life
criteria. um the the committee and the
public input as well, you know, agreed
with um the idea of trying to have
relatively expansive time frames
including from the time of diagnosis of
serious terminal or lifelimiting um
conditions and with the recognition that
end of life is approaching due to
natural aging. So we the the general
idea of trying to have a relatively
expansive and that this is not limited
to immediate uh you know hospice care.
Um we focus some of the idea of
therapeutic um you know team
development. Um and part of that you
know is is the idea that this needs to
extend beyond you know strictly medical
providers and licensed therapists
include you know nurses, paliotative
care um uh more roles such as
psychedelic end of life duas and
chaplain and you know discuss the idea
of developing an entrylevel facilitator
role um for inclusion and this would
obviously overlap with other committees
but that was one area that would we
thought was important to maintain access
and and equity.
We think that um end of life may be
unique among the four indications of of
being able to include family and
caregivers because it's not a specific
diagnosis but it's an end of life
process. And so we're interested in
having life partners, family member, one
other person participate in the
psilocybin assistant therapy to um help
with the end of life care.
um the site came up um and you know with
end of end of life in different um
people's um wellness states the idea of
having homebased end of life care um it
was felt to be particularly important
the idea of coordinating with hospice
organizations home health agencies was
also discussed
um the education and workforce
development um was discussed the main
the main discussion I was that the
feeling that um any everyone who's
involved in offering um uh psilocybin
friend of life care, you know, would
really benefit from there some very
specific education and also we discussed
some that there are actually fuller
programs that are out there where people
can uh can relate that if this is going
to become their primary focus.
um end of life care plans. Um you know
we discussed you that preparation,
integration, psilocybin do number of
sessions may some of those will be
specific to end of life care as well as
involvement of family and caregivers and
you know similarly to um you know what
Desbo was mentioning the idea that this
will overlap with other um other groups.
But we wanted to focus some some on the
actual specifics that are important
friend of life career and then that you
know our part of our role would be to
periodic review of scientific um
scientific literature. So that was our
that was our main focus as far as the um
as the content. We decided that we're
going to meet every two weeks and we
have a meeting set up for um uh set up
for next week. One one thing we decided
in our group is that we're going to try
um to probably put in about a 15 minute
sort of inservice educational session at
least for the first few months to to
bring everybody up to um you know up to
speed on some of the issues. You know an
example was um mentioning that there are
specific issues as far as doses and
stuff with end of life care from a
vernacope point of view understanding
the role of psychedelic death doula. So,
we're going to do some some inservicing
education for our committee as well.
>> That about wraps it up. Um, I say we're
looking forward to our next meeting next
week.
>> Perfect. Well, thank you for all of
that. That sounds like you guys are
doing some great work in that committee.
Um I completely agree with the openness
of having end of life care especially
because paliative of care um can include
things like hospice but it can also be
areas where we can may still be able to
cure it but we just want to make them
more comfortable and take care of the
people that are you know suffering. So I
really appreciate all the work that you
are doing. Um next is research and
continuous improvement with Dan
Jennings.
>> I appreciate it and thank you very much.
We had our meeting uh last Friday at
9:00. Uh we'll probably be on a two-eek
cadence as well at the same time. So,
we'll plan on meeting next uh Friday at
9:00 as well. We had about 20
individuals that came to the meeting. A
lot of great discussion. We focused on a
couple of different things. First was uh
we don't have bylaws. We just have some
norms that we center around uh so that
we can just kind of uh get our work done
at this moment. our responsibilities in
that group that we wanted to kind of
take on first uh our core data elements.
If we're looking to track uh information
that's going in and out of the uh
medical psilocybin uh program, we wanted
to make sure there were some good data
elements and then also some research and
best practice or uh references
materials. So, we worked on uh a set of
both. uh we got through presenting both
of those two sets to the group and our
intentionality is for our next meeting
where we'll be able to kind of come to a
consensus about the lists of the data
elements and the research and best
practices that were presented. Uh we'll
continue to have that same flow. So as
individuals uh will present uh research
we one of our norms we focused on was it
should be uh based upon primary research
not secondary tertiary and also to be
very aware of biases that would show up
in that research. So what we're looking
to do is if somebody has some material
to present that this should be something
we should look at as an advisory board
that this group could look at that and
then have good discussion around that uh
research area talk about it and then
come to a voted consensus to make
recommendations that that would be
something we could look at. Uh Desba
made a very good comment in our um in
our meeting that this RACI
uh committee is almost like a a two-way
street. So meaning that there's a lot of
research that all of y'all inside of
your committees may rely on and also
reference. Uh we would like to have that
information. So if you from a committee
uh chair have research that you're
using, if you would send it on our way,
we could include it into that list. So
we would just want to make a really good
continuum bibliography of the research
we focus on. Another thing that came out
from the discussion of that group was um
the idea that this should be adaptive
regulations. So this committee may be
one that as this program gets
implemented and off the ground that
could be kind of an entry point for
here's some new research that committees
could look at to make changes and
adaptive in those regulations that they
came up with. Uh we also in the data
elements had some very good discussion
around different uh things. One of the
things that came up since this committee
may have um a footprint in outcome
monitoring and adverse event reporting
standards. The discussion came around
that maybe instead of calling it adverse
events, it's challenging events. Uh
words do matter. So it might be
something that we look at and we'll take
a vote on in that sense as well. Uh
we'll also be doing some ad hoc work
assignments or homework. And so uh our
next meeting we're going to start to uh
center around uh what are the next steps
for this group to work on so that we can
be uh helpful to all of y'all on
committees and to the program as well
and kind of outline what we can do to
help with. Uh Ian, I did want to ask you
a question though. One of the things we
do have in our committee
responsibilities
uh is the uh
risk screening and medication
interaction guidance. I kind of have a
feeling that probably y'all in the
dosing committee are probably going to
be focusing on that as well. So can give
me some direction if that's something we
put on the back burner if that's
something that dosing will take care or
just tell me how we should so that we
work together on that.
>> Yeah. So, I know that the um the patient
qualification and safety committee is
going to be creating an a list of
patient exclusion criteria which will
include uh medication interactions. Um
so, I guess uh not I guess I put that
into your language because I wanted the
research and continuous improvement to
look at it after the fact and say,
"Okay, well, we've had a lot that have
taken this medication and now they're
having adverse reactions or challenging
reactions." Um and so just so that
there's a way to implement and fully
flesh out the program because when one
of the things that I imagine is that the
continuous and continuous improve
research and continuous improvement
Jesus um part of it would be an ongoing
committee. Um and so even after we have
everything, you know, set up fully
functional, if people still want to
present evidence and still have um
things to challenge us on, I wanted to
give them an open door to say, "Hey, you
can 100% work for this program. If you
disagree with something we came up with,
here's the avenue to change it." Um and
that's kind of why I gave you guys that
authority. It wasn't necessarily to say
this is your first priority. It was just
like if if something happens and people
are very upset which I don't imagine
happening but that way there is that
that path there is a path forward for
communication and collaboration.
>> Perfect. Thanks for clarifying that. I
wanted to make sure. So uh that's kind
of where I looked at this is this
committee will continue to work on some
of that adaptive uh things later on. So
appreciate the clarification.
>> All right. And then with that it leaves
just two committees left. the patient
qualification and dosage administration
and clinical practice. So for patient
qualification and safety, we had our uh
beginning meeting. We adopted bylaws and
we also adopted definitions for the
initial qualifying conditions. So the
legislature had um passed that four
qualifying conditions would exist.
Substance use disorder, PTSD, treatment
resistant depression, and end of life
care. So we just put them to ICD10 codes
in order to make it, you know, more
standardized to work across the
committees because if I'm treating a
specific ICD10 code, then that I can set
the dosage for that code, I can then set
um patient safety standards for that
code and work to make sure it is flushed
out completely considering their
diagnosis and what is kind of happening
with them, especially when we're given,
you know, terms that are not medical
terms by the legislature. So substance
use disorder is not a medical term. We
would use the specific use disorder. So
um empetamine use disorder, um cannabis
use disorder, whatever it happens to be,
that's what we would use. So I just
provided ICD and 10 codes and that's
what the patient qualification and
safety committee has been up to. Right
now, they're pending a meeting on
February
20th to um flush out those exclusion
criteria, make sure that we have a good
baseline for where we're starting um
this program and making sure we're
starting on the foot of patient safety
first. Um the dosage administration
clinical practice committee has met.
They have adopted bylaws um and they are
just working to
interpret those um
codes from the patient qualification
committee and set up a do dosage regime
for each um
diagnosis because as we know in medicine
oftent times the dose to treat one
disorder is not the dose to treat
another disorder. Um and that is my
update from the committees. So we can
now go ahead and move to other business.
Is there any other discussion that we
have from our board members?
Seeing no discussion, I guess I'll kind
of open the floor to um a couple things
that I have been thinking about. M so
one of the big um components that we
have to have in this program is
propagation
um and cultivation of our u mushrooms.
So I personally would like the board to
set a goal of having them completed by
May. That would give us time to um allow
the secretary to either approve or deny
our recommendations. It then gives us
time for the department to fully
promulgate those rules and allow us to
have the producers begin because we are
going to need the producers ready months
before we have our first patients. So I
will just open the discussion for that
if anyone has any questions, comments,
concerns.
Um, sorry. Hold on. Sorry.
Uh,
when you say May, can I just get a
clarification? You said again, um, to
adopt something by May so that we can
start having
the patients. Um,
>> the cultivation by May.
>> The cultivation.
>> So, just the growing the mushrooms. I
don't think we're going to have the
whole program ready by May,
>> but I just want to have us to be able to
start licensing those growers. That way,
in 2027 when we have our first patients,
the the supply already exists.
That way, we're not trying to run at the
last minute to grow these mushrooms.
Instead, we can say, "Okay, we have it
licensed. We have it tested now in the
real world, and we can say, okay, this
has been adopted. This is working out.
Now we feel safe to take our first
patients.
>> Um I would really appreciate this might
has to go into public um comment
territory. Um but what I'm understanding
at least from my p perspective is it may
need to be reverse engineered in terms
of timeline
by what we have established already to
do the testing.
um what what facilities that and uh
framework and structure do we have
already in place for those things and
what are those standards
um prior to being able to figure out
what that looks like. And that's just
with my limited thinking as far as like
what needs to what needs to happen first
with with the timelines. Um
because I think that there if we're
doing this all inhouse and when I say
in-house I mean within New Mexico um I'm
I'm actually don't know where the
facilities are for these types of things
and who has it and I know that that
might be also in equity access uh
considerations like who actually has
some of this equipment can be costly
especially when it comes to like large
batches of this Um, I know that
individual testing might be possible,
but what are those things that we're
looking for? Um, and then also, uh, how
long it takes to get those results back?
And so my first thought is just what are
the what is that, you know, what is the
structure that's in place before we can
do the testing and what are we looking
at when it comes to the testing?
and then from there we can figure out
what that looks like. But that's just my
first thought. Sorry.
>> Yeah, no worries. Um actually while I
was in the propagation committee, Rio
Grand Analytics had already basically
explained it was the same technology
that they're using for um cannabis. So
our infrastructure is already pretty
existent. But I will go ahead and turn
to Dominic. He had a comment.
>> Yeah, thank you Ian and Desba. I
completely understand what you're
talking about. Um what Ian was
mentioning in the beginning is we do
have to prioritize the cultivation and
the testing sort of together in parallel
so that we can ensure that there is
product for those first patients. And
when we look at it from a standpoint of
seeing the first patients in December of
2026, the cultivators are going to need
several months for that. The points you
raised about how long will it take to
get the products then tested, all of
that work really means we need to be
able to license producers or cultivators
really by this summer. And then as well
also the uh potential labs. Now again,
as Ian has said earlier and I've said in
pretty much most of the meetings, it's
not going to have everybody who
potentially is going to be engaging in
the program as cultivators, lab testing,
and all of that in by next December. But
once we open those applications and can
start taking them, we do need to have at
least a few to be able to produce um to
be able to produce products and to be
able to test them. And so that's a part
of the process, but it's not like we're
going to open the applications and then
just shut them closed. It's going to be
an ongoing process. So in order for us
to be able to have licensing by this
summer, it means those rules with regard
to cultivation and testing, we need
those sooner by this spring essentially
so that we can have that process. And it
doesn't mean that the other parts of the
process aren't happening. the ideas of
the patient aspects, the dosage aspects,
all of that is still continuing to move
forward and we'll have those by really
figure by about early fall to midfall to
have all of that in place. But we can't
see any patients at all if we don't
already have a product able for them or
timed out for people to be able to
utilize that medication in December when
those patients are seen. I hope that
helps clarify it a little bit. So, it
doesn't mean all the other work stops
and we wait until this part is done.
They're all happening in parallel. It
just means we're going to prioritize the
regulations for cultivation and testing
first. If that helps, I hope it helps.
And then, uh, Chris, you had a comment.
You're muted, Chris.
>> I was going to say that was just kind of
going to be in line with what I was
thinking. I'm going to uh attempt to
work through the cultivation piece first
and then get the testing. If I need to,
we can kind of flip-flop meetings um to
kind of do those concurrently. Um, but
uh I would like that to kind of be a
more phased approach if I can and get
the the cultivation piece out uh first
in the next couple months and then the
testing piece out um following that and
then put off all of the distribution,
transportation
product production type stuff until
afterwards. Um as I I feel like we're
going to end up taking a lot of that uh
from marijuana laws that currently
exist. So
that that's kind of my thought process
on it and we're going to dive into
cultivation on the next meeting. So
>> perfect. Thank you. And Larry,
>> yeah, I I I support the idea of like,
you know, of frontloading frontloading
that. I also agree though in Desbos
somewhere. We're just going to have to
see what happens as we're doing this. I
mean, and see what obstacles that we
encounter. But clearly the propagation
seems first. I I I do want to throw
though quickly into the mix that um
training has to get and started pretty
quickly too. I mean you know at least in
other states the training programs are
you know five to six months they have to
be either created or we have to you know
decide about reciprocity with other
states and how we're doing that part of
it. And so I um I guess I'm I'm jumping
on the timetable bandwagon and
suggesting that that training has to be
um done soon so that there is somebody
who's skilled in uh skilled and can be
approved to be um offering the therapy.
>> Perfect. Thank you. And Brenda,
>> yeah, I agree. Since I'm the last um
person to have these meetings, um this
is all coming in like um full scope here
with everybody in playing their parts
here. Um but yes, I agree with Larry the
um having people that are already gone
through programs here, what that's going
to look like and that's what I'm going
to be opening up uh in our meetings.
It's uh um already have all of that um
uploaded for for our meeting. So, uh
this is going to be one of those things
where um it's going to be pretty much a
template of working with what people
have already learned in their trainings.
and uh uh will we be letting in people
that are already trained into this
program and um hit the ground running uh
according to all of the um the rules and
regulations and the training. So, um I
was thinking, you know, of having at
least uh as many meetings as possible
because this is a lot for um many people
that are already here that want to start
practicing. Um a question um just
talking with friends and all of that. um
will we be need to have licensing for
all the people that are already
certified
uh in um you know in their education and
what that's going to look like. So
there's a lot to be discussed in in the
meeting for training and education.
>> Thank you. I really appreciate that. and
and yeah, I I don't know if you want my
opinion, but I think it would be
perfectly okay to offer reciprocity as
long as we gave a um New Mexico specific
course just so that we make sure that
they're informed of our laws. Um but I
think that that's great work and I
appreciate all that you have been doing.
Uh Desba has a comment.
>> Yes. So, kind of at least to summarize
like what we're talking about right now,
a couple of things. Um,
so sometimes just for the sake I ask
questions maybe that I may have like um
I'm trying to learn myself and come up
to speed but then also what I feel like
is the temperature that might be
potential other questions that maybe
other everyone else might have and it's
also basically just for clarification of
what's going on. Um but it's good that
we're able to um clarify those points.
Um, so yeah, totally. What I'm what I'm
understanding right now at least and
just uh for the sake of clearing it up
is that we're trying to figure out at
least
the already established people who are
on the side of propagation and also on
the side of training, already doing the
work, have done the work in their own
capacity, but who are here in New Mexico
specifically.
Um now even if they have training from
elsewhere where we're going to look at
the reciprocity for that but then also
cultivators
who may already be establishing their
work have already done their work and
are already using the testing. So those
people in those capacities and let's
just say professional people in those
capacities relying not necessarily
relying but maybe utilizing their
expertise in those fields to help get
this first segment going by the end of
the year. And then from there, we're
continuing to create more um
workflow for when it when it becomes
more open to the broader range of
10 cultivators, 20 cultivators, 10
licensed um professionals in their
various capacities, whether they're
indigenous leaders, nurses, um
therapists, and in any of those things.
Um is what I'm hearing. The one thing
I'm thinking that would probably be
useful as far as who loves to do these
types of things is a v visual timetable
that can be manipulated to kind of at
least plop down what we're looking at
and then we can figure out from there we
can move it around and similar to that
back to Dan's um how research and um is
going to to be utilized in the various
different ways whether it's what
messages work, what training works,
because this is going to be a
neverending
um
I can't think of the word, but it's just
going to be never ending in terms of
getting it right and how we're working
through it. I believe um Dominic gave
the example of cannabis, you know, 20
years ago it started and now we're still
kind of working through the kinks and
trying to figure out what works for New
Mexico um and its constituents. So that
was just a kind of summarization and
also an added comment.
>> Yeah. And I really appreciate your um
your input. I definitely do agree with
the you know the reciprocity. Um one of
the things that I know from my
experience in living in Texas is that
their medical cannabis program had two
dispensaries. And so what that meant for
prices was crazy. what you could buy for
$15 here was $70 over there. And so I
think that if we offer reciprocity for
things that are not, you know, going to
change between states, like cultivation
is not going to change much. If you can
grow a mushroom in Oregon, you can
probably grow it in New Mexico. It'll be
a little more difficult. Our our weather
is a little less friendly, but um we can
definitely work with that. And so um
anything we can do to expand and on the
competition in the medical psilocybin
market is really important to me because
I want the best quality medicine for the
best price for our patients. Um Dominic
had a question or comment. Yeah, I just
wanted to say um so part of what some of
this conversation is is about creating
that priority so that we can assist from
a department standpoint in helping to
create that visual that you're asking
for at DeadSpot. And so if if this group
is in agreement with the cultivation and
then the testing uh you know we can
start working on that and then we can
add in those other pieces as the various
committees say okay what does it look
like for our timeline and when to get
these proposed regulations and sort of
moving uh forward with that. And so
essentially helping to create that
project plan. But like right now what
you've got at the moment is the
committees are gathering information,
hearing from the public. And so now is
the point to start creating that plan
and and I will say that as a department
we do have some ideas and things like
that, but we also want to make sure that
this is being done transparently and is
actually having that input from all of
you and not just the board members, but
the public as well. And so we don't want
to unduly influence that. And so that's
a part of it. And so now as the
committees continue to meet forward and
start to think about those timelines and
not just hearing some of that public
information, we can start creating that
project plan and those visuals for you.
>> Perfect. Thank you, Dominic and Chris.
still muted, Chris.
>> I'll get there eventually. Sorry, guys.
Um
I have two thoughts. Uh the first is
that um I think the training piece
really should be probably co-prioritized
at the beginning. We I feel like we
really need to get our our people up to
to speed on that as quickly as possible
because it's going to take more time
than we think. think I'm in a training
program in Colorado so I can help out
with Dr. Leman's study and it it takes a
while. So, um, and then my second
thought is on reciprocity with the
cultivators. I think we have plenty of
cultivators here in New Mexico that are
up and ready to go right now and and I
don't think that's going to be a
problem. um they may have to make some
adjustments, but I also feel like that
some of them have uh
been aware that this might be coming and
and can make this happen. So
that's all I have.
>> All right. Well, thank you so much for
that. And
I do believe this program should be New
Mexico first. Um I just think uh that in
terms of reciprocity
it can allow expertise from different
areas to flow in and especially because
this is the first time our state is
doing something like this I do want
people who have a lot of experience and
I do know that there are plenty of
homegrown um maybe they don't want to
get interested in that. I do think we
should have a preference for our New
Mexican growers, but I don't think it
should be exclusive to New Mexican
growers. I think there's expertise in
many parts of this country, um, not just
the state of New Mexico, although I do
think we are the best.
>> All right. Um, so if you guys wanted to
set some, you know, preliminary dates,
we could do that. say um
we could do March 1st have all of the
lab testing information
um ready by April
15th we would have um the lab testing
and the growing requirements pushed to
the board. That way the board could as a
whole review it, see what it is, how
it's um you know doing and then in our
meeting in May we could um get along
with that. How about I have a question
from Dominic.
>> Um Ian, I actually would would recommend
that we do that by February. And the
reason I say that is the process with
regard to uh regulations is that we
actually have to have public hearings
outside of this board. So they're just
regulatory public hearings. Uh I
shouldn't say just, they are very
important, but they are regulatory
public hearings and we have to provide
30 days notice. And so I would say that
we present by uh midFebruary as far as a
draft with regard to cultivation and
testing. Um and then I would say by the
beginning of March and this is what um
you know addresses some of the concerns
that people have because again while we
say prioritize we're only talking small
differences in time frames. So I would
say some of those others as far as
training and uh certification in March
in early March. Um, and what that that
does and then the others can sort of
follow afterwards a little bit. What
that really does is that allows for the
30 days notice for public hearings to
occur, those public hearings for the
rules to occur and then adoption of them
after that. Um, and so I just want to
suggest that as far as timeline, just
looking at those other pieces that also
need to be there because it's not just
the board doing that recommendation and
then that them getting um promulgated.
The rules actually have to go through a
separate rule making process.
>> Yes. Um, and then Chris,
>> I'm sorry. Did you did you say March for
testing and cultivation?
>> So I had said March. Dominic had
corrected me to say um February to allow
for the full promaguation um procedure.
It involves a lot of um public
discourse. It involves a lot of posting
in official registers and um making sure
that that information is available to
the public and can be debated and um
that all the parties that are going to
be impacted can speak on it. And that
takes um a long time. If you want to
know like an example of this in the real
world, look at the federal
reclassification of marijuana. It has
been pending for 2 years um because
we've been waiting on public hearings
and judges changing and things like
that. So it it is a long and strenuous
process. So he had actually recommended
mid-March or I mean midFebruary for
cultivation and testing and then
mid-March for training and
certification.
>> That's pretty that's a pretty quick
timeline.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, it is a little bit quick. Um but I
do believe that there with this it's an
effort to push our resources toward um
that cultivation and testing. We can if
you need assistance you know chairing
some committee meetings or um you know
whatever you need to help you support
you and get you through that we can do
it. Um, but in order to meet that
administrative, you know, deadline of
2027, we have to have these things ready
to go through the full public hearing
process and ready to go through all of
those rulemaking procedures in order to
allow this to actually become official.
And then Larry.
>> Yeah, this is really um Dom, this is a
question for you. One thing that's come
up in um discussions came up in the end
of life is if we're going to have like a
facilitator um similar to what they have
in Colorado and Oregon which you does it
similar similar training does that
actually have to go back to the
legislature to create that or is that
something that can be done at the level
of um do and the secretary?
>> So can you explain a little bit more
exactly what you mean Larry?
>> Sure. So, um, you know, the, um, you
know, what what they do in Colorado,
really, everybody needs to go through
some facilitator training to be
approved. Um, and they actually have
like a licensed facilitator position
there. If we were going to do something
like that in New Mexico, just came up
with the psychedelic death doula idea,
and this person would be a direct entry.
They're not a therapist or a physician.
Do we need to actually have a a bill to
create such a position or is can we do
that internally?
>> Okay. So, gotcha. I was uh just trying
to figure out as far as certification
aspects of it. No, it does not need to
go back to the legislature. Um that is
something that as the regulations get
promulgated was assigned to uh
technically it's to the department
because we're the ones who will be the
department will be who actually
promulgates the rules. And so um with
regard to that it does not need to go uh
back to the legislature. It stays and
remains with the department and of
course with this advisory board for
making those recommendations. So for
example is the question that's come up
with reciprocity if uh and this would
fall under uh the the training
committee. So with Brenda, um if that
training committee made the
recommendations and this board accepted
them for reciprocity and here are the
conditions for reciprocity, which I
would say would be, you know, uh just to
sort of throw out there and of course
other details to be determined, but that
someone already be certified um in
either a training program that has
already been um deemed an accepted
program in either Oregon or Colorado,
that they prove that. And then as Ian
said, have a module which we're looking
from a department standpoint on creating
that would be specific for New Mexico
about the New Mexico statutes,
regulations and of course the protocols
as those come forward that that be then
available and they have to complete that
as well. And then in that kind of a
situation the reciprocity could work. So
we already have quite a few people I
mean many people have reached out saying
I've been certified and trained in
Oregon. I'm a certified facilitator. I'm
in this. And so that would allow for the
people who already are to be able to do
this a little bit earlier and as well as
having that reciprocity to be able to
have what are the requirements for
training programs moving forward and to
have that available. And I know there's
been a lot of people who have asked and
said people have to be trained instate.
We want only people who are New Mexicans
uh who are doing this or who are living
in New Mexico. And those are some of the
details that the that the training
committee can really be looking at is
what would work from an equity
standpoint, what would work in order to
make this fair. Some people have
suggested for example doing while we
initially do this with regard to
reciprocity for the programs from other
states that there be essentially like a
sunset clause so that if you haven't
done that by a certain date then at that
point you have to go through a program
that has been established in New Mexico
and so that sort of thing. So it sort of
helps in both areas where first you have
people who already have been trained and
then it focuses on people who are
already here rather than continuing to
have people just essentially coming in
from elsewhere. And so those are some
things that have come up and that I know
Brenda's smiling and laughing because I
know we've talked a little bit about
this and some of the other folks are
too. And thank you all as far as the
applause. That's really great to hear
that there's a lot of support on that.
But those are some of the ideas that
have been coming out. We've actually
been talking about them for months. I
can't even remember. The first time I
think we talked about this was during
legislative session last year, so
probably a year.
>> And it was one of the reasons why we
actually do not have that as a
requirement to have to go back to the
legislature to be able to uh make those
requirements as far as the certification
of practitioners.
So, I know that was a really long
answer, but I see all these messages in
the chat, and I was trying to kind of
cover answering a lot of those, and I
hope I was able to do that. Um, and so,
thank you. And Larry, I hope that
answered the question in a long
roundabout way.
>> Dom, super helpful, very clear.
Appreciate it.
>> Thank you.
>> Perfect. And then I have Brenda raising
her hand.
you Dominic.
Uh this has been um yeah this has been
one of the the focus uh for my first
meeting is uh the recip reciprocity uh
with all of this and um trying to do
this as um quickly efficiently and to
the point with the training and um like
myself I'm I was trained in maps and
spent thousands and thousands of dollars
just like many people here in our chat
that have been trained. And so, uh,
thank you so much for explaining that in
a nutshell because we're, uh, folks,
we're going to be getting into it and,
uh, now the deadline is March,
hope the end of March.
So that means probably um I'm going to
try to have as many meetings as possible
between now and then because that's um a
very short timeline, but we have a
template to go by. Um, the majority of
people here have been been trained um
and meet the requirements for New Mexico
um and and like um Ian said have um like
just classes just for New Mexico that
are um not going to take up a whole lot
of time like months and months of time.
maybe just a a class that covers a an
awful lot of what we've been talking
about here in order to get people uh
trained and ready to go. Um and that
includes
everything, you know, uh from history
all the way up to dosing to what we're
doing right now. And this is uh going to
flex and change a little bit here and
there, but I think we can I think we can
do this.
I completely agree and thank you so much
for your comments. Um I do also want to
include because I do know quite a few
stories like this where um New Mexicans
went to Colorado, got licensed and are
practicing there
>> because that was available to them. They
wanted to work in the psychedelic space
and that was already available and so
they got their lensure um in Colorado. I
think it would be um fantastic if this
board could work to bring those New
Mexicans back home and um allow them to
work in our psychedelic program here. Um
I do know a lot of people that this
medicine is is is incredibly important
to them and it's incredibly important to
me too, but where they wanted to devote
their lives to this and they couldn't do
that in this state at the time. And so I
would it would I don't think that just
because they are licensed in another
state means they are necessarily from
that state. It just means that's where
they happen to get a yes and we're
willing to be trained.
All right.
And then
so uh if we wanted to go ahead and just
um adopt those original deadlines, we
could say February 15th for um
cultivation and testing and then March
15th for um training and education. Does
that sound good to everyone?
>> All right.
>> How about Wait a second. February 15th.
That's a month for all of the
cultivation and testing.
I think this is way too quick. Give me
till the end of February.
>> Chris, those are drafts.
>> Okay.
>> Not like the final like this needs to be
the the thing done. These are just we
need them to
be prepared. That way the board can have
something to discuss and to full fully
move forward with those recommendations.
I don't anticipate that these are going
to be perfect when they come out of
committee any committee action that it's
going to be perfect spoton. Um I think
we have to do our our job to
independently verify all of the
information we um receive and not just
go off of based on the authority of the
person or on the ethos of that person.
We must look at it independently. And
so, um, while yes, it is a little bit
quick to have those out, if we want to
still keep the deadlines that we were,
um, trying to, it would be, um,
February would be the best time to have
it done. Um,
that process for making a rule and
administrative procedures take a long
time.
Um, so I just want to point that out
there. It's not that we are trying to
say we need perfect final done ready for
posting to everyone but we need um at
least something that we can begin our
discussions off of. And I also want to
turn the mic to Desba. She had her hand
raised.
>> Yeah. I just for the sake of clarity,
can you um restate the ask for those two
committees in like a one-s sentence
thing? What was the what was the ask for
the deadlines? the specific
>> so uh for the um propagation committee
the deadline was February 15th to have
um cultivation and testing standards
>> a draft
>> yeah a draft
>> and then um education and training I
wanted um by March 15th them to have
their draft of um lensure and training
requirements
Ian, this is Larry. I'm I'm sorry. I'm
I'm on my phone now because I got bumped
off the computer. Um I I think the March
15th for the training is probably too
soon. There's much more intersection
between all the different committees. I
mean, we we need to figure out what what
some of like the model that we're doing
is here. And so I I would I would be
hesitant to set some a date for that. I
mean, we we have major issues that we
have to define. Like in other words,
what makes you eligible? who actually
gives you a diagnosis, how does that
relate into that? So, I would be I'd be
careful. I mean, it honestly took
Colorado two years. I'm al totally in
favor of um trying to accelerate it, but
like two months does not sound
reasonable to me for for the training
part. And I'm the one who advocated
accelerating the training part. I think
I just think it needs a little more time
than that.
>> Yeah. And I would be um open to that. I
do just want to stress like if I had all
the time in the world, I would take all
the time in the world. This is really
about just um trying to get this ready
for those first patients. Um I would
much rather set restrictive goals and
then fail to meet our goals than to set
really loose goals and not get
accomplished our overarching um you know
priority for this year. So, I'm not
saying
like it's all over if we don't get it
done by March 15th, but I think
sometimes in um psychology, if you give
someone a higher bar than they're able
to reach, they jump higher. So, um
that that's kind of where I am at with
this, but I will um it looked like
Dominic had a comment.
So, so here's what I'm kind of asking
and Desbos sort of hit on it a little
bit earlier and I had made the comment
about project plan. Part of the reason
why from a department standpoint we are
asking for some of this is re again it's
not a final version. It is a draft.
We're not asking for approval by this.
And so by doing this what it means is
for example and I'll just use the
propagation. So the cultivation piece is
with the cultivation piece by February
then what can happen is the this board
can look at it and say you know what
what you have here is good bad needs
improvement and here are the areas that
are missing so that we're working with a
little bit more specifics rather than
the broad generalities and I would say
the same with the training because
you're right Larry it may be that it's
still another two three months after
that but that gives sort of a beginning
basis to start saying what are we
missing? What have we looked at? What
have we not looked at? And how do we do
that? And so when we say having that
presented for this board, it's not
saying it's going to be a final version.
It's really starting to say here are
some deadlines for some of these items
and here's what we really kind of need
to move forward. Not final versions and
all that. Although I mean if they if the
committees are able to get final
versions that's fantastic but that's not
really what the anticipation is. It's to
say hey by February middle of February
we will have the beginnings and our
draft for cultivation. What other things
do we need? What is missing? What hasn't
been considered? And what is good? Does
that help? And so a and so for example
this first draft it may very well then
be at that meeting the next step is okay
we looked at it we said you need to
really work on these areas and parts
come back to the next meeting with that
part completed and sort of doing that as
part of this project plan but without
having some at least deadline started we
could otherwise be spending months just
saying we're gathering information we're
gathering information and never really
putting anything into action. And that's
a part of why we're asking this um from
a department standpoint of we need to
start taking those actions. They're not
going to be perfect. They're not going
to be complete, but we need to start
taking them. And I hope that helps.
John, Mrs. Larry, again, um that that
sounds very reasonable. We're clarifying
that we're going to see a proposal by
mid-March um about facilitation, but we
realize it may take uh substantially
longer or at least some amount longer.
I'm comfortable with that.
>> Perfect. And then Desba,
>> yeah, that's essentially what I was just
going to say as far as, you know,
putting it putting the sticky note on
the whiteboard. This is where we're
starting from with the draft proposals
and then that's where our committees are
intersecting with respect to um Larry's
end of life care. What does that look
like for the facilitator and then also
with respect to equity access is you
know does that include indigenous you
know does that include rural areas? Does
that include like you know the equity of
the training and the cost and
effectiveness and what does that look
like when it comes to reciprocity? So
that's where we start filling in the
holes of each of these different um uh I
don't
can't think of the word agendas I don't
want to say committees but you know and
dosage etc. That's where all of these
different committees are intersecting
and adding in our two cents with respect
to what the public needs into those um
places, which is where the public, we
need the input from everyone else to say
that this is what New Mexico residents
need for this for this, you know, for
for um for our care and our our
well-being.
>> Yeah, I completely agree with that. I
mean, um, I have always said, you know,
the people of New Mexico have so much
more knowledge than the seven of us
combined. There's so much more wealth of
wisdom in our communities. So, um, as
much help as the public is willing to
offer, I I am always, um, willing to
accept. I did want to add um on to what
Dominic was saying um he had also
mentioned in one of our committees that
um the department would be helping to um
kind of bridge the committees helping to
provide uh updates on what's happening
in another. So what I wanted to clarify
with this goal um framing is that we're
not saying suspend every other committee
until this is done. and we're saying no,
continue to work, continue to do your
thing. As we continue to patch holes in
those committees, but we want to say
these we need to get um if like these
pass a committee, then they'll go to the
board and we will take them up and we
these are our priorities, but that
doesn't mean suspend all work in all
other committees. No, we still need to
develop and have questions that need to
be answered and a question answered in
one committee might be useful in another
committee. So it really is about, you
know, collaboration, working together,
and just making sure that, you know, we
have to put something out there. We
could spend eternity saying, "Let's look
at the data. Let's let's continue. No,
we need more. We need more. We need
more." You can continue to do that
indefinitely. Um I don't think I've ever
read a study where at the end it didn't
say, "But more research could be
conducted." Um, so I just wanted to say,
you know, like Dominic said, we make
mistakes. We are people. We are human.
We are going to do human things. So I
just want to let everyone know it's
okay. We are working our best. We are
doing our best. I believe um if each of
you are like me, I am working as hard as
I can to serve the people of New Mexico
who deserve access to this medication.
So um with that, I just wanted to say um
it's not a whole pause. We're just kind
of focusing our intentions.
All right. Any more discussion?
All right. Then I move that we adopt
those um deadlines of February 15th and
March 15th for those drafts
um from the
Why am I blinking?
cultivation and testing and the
education and training respectively.
>> Ian, if I may, I would suggest uh the
February 15th or the closest advisory
board meeting to that date.
>> Okay. So, do you want to do So, how
about we set it to be um
Yeah, I mean that's a fair point. When
do you guys want to have your next
advisory board meeting? That's
also of consideration in setting this.
>> I mean, I nobody wants to hear like it's
a day early, but the 13th is our closest
Friday to it.
>> I would be okay with 13th.
>> Uh, and just as a note, the 13th is one
day that the department would not be
able to provide administrative support
during the meeting. So, uh, I would just
recommend a different date, either the
20th, um, or, uh, the 6th,
uh, or I mean it could be a different
day, but, um, you can go with the 13th.
>> 12, um, because I know the the dosage
administration, no, patient
qualification and safety is meeting on
the 20th.
Um, so if you want to do the 20th at
noon, Brenda, you had a question. No,
>> no.
>> When do you suggest?
>> Yeah, I will be in uh training there.
Um, can we do it the 27th or the 13th?
Well, the 13th we can't, but the 27th.
Is that possible?
>> So, here's what we could do is uh if
you're all okay with this, is we could
have the drafts available for review by
the 13th and the meeting on the 27th.
How does that sound
>> better?
>> I would not be able to make the 27th. I
could do the 26th at like three.
>> Uh yeah,
>> 26 at 3 everyone.
>> Larry, you're speaking but we can't hear
you.
>> Yeah, I I I'm covering a hospital
service. I can't do the the 26th. I can
do the 27th.
I mean, if you guys want and if you're
willing to run the meeting, you guys can
do the 20 um
what was it? The 27th,
>> right? That's what we were saying.
>> That's up to Dan, right?
>> That's the 27th at 9:00.
>> Uh yeah, I can I can chair if you would
like me to. I I
>> Okay.
It's I mean up to you if you wanted to
have like the you know that involvement
and it but if you're not able to then we
can also catch up later too.
>> I'm going to definitely try to move
around my schedule and see if I can make
it but just in case I want you to you
know be prepared. Um
>> but yeah the 27th at what time do we
agree on?
>> 9:00 the same time as well.
>> Okay. nine o'clock at 27th
>> and and if you all
>> so we will say the um drafts are due by
the 27th at 9.
>> I Ian I would say the drafts due on the
13th and then consideration on the 27th.
>> Okay. Draft's due on the 13th,
consideration on the 27th. Is everyone
good with that?
>> Sorry, what what month are we talking
about?
>> February.
Yeah, that's okay.
>> Desba.
>> Yeah. And so just again for
clarification, sorry I shouldn't keep
prefacing in that, but um if we have the
draw due on the 13th then Dominic and
Ian, that does allow for the review for
the admin to post it and then public can
see it and do their homework. All of us
can do our homework
prior to the 27th.
>> Correct. And that's why that's why I'm
suggesting we post it by the 13th and
have those drafts there and then you all
have them and the public has them
available to review uh prior to the
meeting on the 27th. So that'll give
about two weeks for people to review and
look at them
>> and and everything.
>> Yes.
>> What time on the 27th?
>> 9. Okay.
All right. Now that we've set our
cultivation goal, um we can either set
the the training and education goal at
the next meeting or we can set it um to
be with the 27th. Which would you guys
prefer?
Cuz it is approaching the beginning of
March, which is where Dominic had
originally said the training and
education might be due. So, we should um
if we want we could push it to be with
the 27th or we could have a separate
meeting for the um
training and education. Dominic,
>> uh I would recommend we do a similar
process and where we say we will post
the draft by the end of business on the
27th for that one and then it be
considered at the next meeting. So
again, people have time to review and
look at it and that it gives a little
separation between the two drafts so
people aren't trying to do too much
>> with the caveat and and understanding
Larry's position as well with the caveat
that the training may not be fully
complete. It is just a draft and
starting point.
>> Yes. All right. Well, that all sounds
good to me. Uh Chris,
>> can we set our our follow on board
meeting, too? Would
it be helpful for people? I I like to
have a little bit more time to
or uh lead time on my schedule.
>> So, the first Friday after the 15th
would be the 20th of March. Did you guys
want to do that?
If we're making recommendations on the
27th
um for education, wouldn't we want to to
review those sooner than the 20? So the
27th is going to be um the
cultivation and laboratory testing. Then
in March, we're going to make the um
training and education committee do. So,
um,
originally I had said March 15th, but
the closest Friday to that is March
20th, or we could go before it and do
March 13th. Um,
Chris,
uh, I can't do the 13th, but,
um, it it seems like if we're going to
have the draft due on February 27th for
the education, we should we should meet
before
the 20th of March.
Okay. Yeah. Uh so the only other
Friday in March would be the 6th. Um
but outside of outside of that it would
be the 20th or the 27th. Um the 27th I
want to remind you the 27th of February
is for that cultivation and testing. I'm
looking at the 20th of March for um
training and educ training and
education.
So, what I will go ahead and do is I
will um drop the meeting after the next
one from this discussion and I'll send
out a a scheduling thing and we will be
able to pick a date that works best for
all of us in March. Um that way it's not
like just throwing out random days and
coming back. Does that sound good to
everyone?
>> Cool. All right, I will turn over to the
department for public comment.
Okay, thank you. Um, Adrian, I believe
you will be um, uh, handling our muting
and unmuting. Um, just so that everybody
knows, if you are interested in public
comment in speaking, just raise your
hand in Teams. And if you're on a
computer, you can click on the hand icon
that's near the top of the Teams window
and underneath it, it says raise. Or if
you are on a f on the Teams app on a
phone, then you click on the three dots,
the ellipse in the menu, and then the
hand icon will appear and you can select
it. It may be a little different
depending what model and operating
system your phone is. Um, if you are
joining through voice only on a phone,
press star five to raise and then again
to lower your hand. Once you've been
called upon, you will be able to unmute.
To unmute uh on Teams on a computer or
on the phone app, you click on the
microphone icon. On a computer, it is in
the upper right area of the Teams
window. And on a phone, it is usually in
the lower left of the Teams app.
However, again, different models or
operating systems may have the icon in a
different location. If you are on a
telephone and voice only, press star six
to unmute yourself once you are called
upon. Thank you. And Adrian, I'll turn
it over to you.
>> I appreciate you. Thank you, Dominic.
And just as a friendly reminder, once
your credentials have been enabled,
there is a 3minut limit.
Up first to requesting to speak, uh my
apologies in advance if I mispronunciate
your name. It's Hanifha Nio Washington.
Hanifeha, your microphone has been
enabled. Will you please unmute
yourself?
>> Thank you. Can you hear me?
Yes.
>> Okay. Wonderful. Good morning everyone.
Thank you so much. Um really appreciate
the work of the DO and of this amazing
advisory board. My name is Hanife
Washington. I am a new resident to New
Mexico since August and I am one of the
co-directors of the psychedelic mental
health access alliance and we have had
the joy of working with Dr. Larry Leman
um with at the University of New Mexico
toward the development and
implementation of the GPAT study that is
due to begin um in 2020 in this first
quarter of 2026. Um I had a
recommendation in terms of the
suggestion for subcommittees. Um I
really appreciate the work that Desba's
doing in the equity, access, and
cultural considerations. I really do
want to lift up and this is something
that I believe Denali Wilson from half
mentioned in one of the previous
committees around a really need to look
at affordability
um reimbursement and Medicaid pathways
to cover this type of work um and uh
care and so wanting to just lift that up
for the advisory board to consider the
developments of that subcommittee
specifically around or talking about
equity. It's a pretty big word. It
covers a lot of aspects. So I wonder if
the subcommittee as it stands is can
really focus on what does what I was
focusing on and talking about earlier in
terms of where are the intersections
around equitable practices and and um
processes within the the subcommittees
looking at cultural considerations and
access. Um, but really, you know,
looking at who's going to pay for this,
how is it going to be paid for, and
really having a subcommittee that
focuses on financing, uh, right,
reimbursement and equitable access in
terms of affordability. That's what I
have for now. Thank you all so much.
>> Thank you.
Next up to speak is Denali Wilson.
Denali, your microphone credentials have
been enabled. Will you please unmute
yourself?
Good morning everyone. Um
I'm grateful to be here this morning and
have the opportunity to address the
board and and the department. Um
there are a lot of things covered and so
sorry if I I jump around trying to keep
to my to my three minutes. um grateful
to Heneifea and the Psychedelic Mental
Health Access Alliance for reviving this
uh recommendation around um third party
payers. Maybe the timing for that could
be after we meet these first two uh
draft deadlines in uh February and
March. uh the sub the board could um
consider the recommendations for for
additional subcommittees to support the
work the work of the advisory board um
on the the timeline and the the
acceleration. I
I I think I think it's going to be a
real challenge. Um, I I want to support
the board and the department in in
meeting what's been requested by the
governor and the secretary.
I think that the the motto um that will
make it happen without um you know
creating anything that's that's
difficult to
um to operate under is really going to
be lean regulations. um you know if we
if we're moving forward at a pace where
we recognize that there's more to learn
and um and operate an ability to iterate
and adapt. I I think early regulation
should be as lean as possible. Uh it's
really challenging. Um and Colorado and
Oregon are in a place where um early
very dense regulations then become hard
to correct when it's clear that it's
it's not easy to to operate under
whatever the regulation has that's been
adopted is. In addition to echoing the
um the board's commitment
um or supporting the board's commitment
to also prioritizing training and and
education, I wonder if it might be
really valuable to consider in addition
to to prioritizing what are the training
and education requirements so that
people can operate, finding a way to
authorize
um a a practicum site in New Mexico. um
because it's really prohibitive for um
people who want to be trained to have to
uh travel to Colorado and Oregon. And
while I think reciproc reciprocity is a
really important equity piece, uh we
need to be making sure that we create
opportunities for people based here who
aren't currently licensed um to to
access that training. and the travel
involved um could be cost prohib in
addition to to the um the cost of
tuition could be unnecessarily cost
prohibitive. So I think the department
would be in a place of uh of authorizing
um a a practicum site in New Mexico so
that
>> you have three minutes
>> so that training Thank you. Um that's
all and I'll add the rest to my uh to
the chat.
Thank you.
If anyone else would like to go ahead
and speak.
Perfect. So, I'm sorry, Desba. Go ahead.
Okay. Next up is uh James Brown. James,
your microphone credentials have been
enabled. Will you please unmute
yourself?
Morning everyone and again thank you for
letting me talk today. I just had a few
comments. Um a couple things you know
for qualifications I'm really looking
forward to that meeting with Brenda and
again thank you Brenda for sharing that.
Um one of my thoughts and comments on
that prior to this meeting that meeting
is um access and qualifications for a
variety of people. I would just like
people to think about that is who has
already been trained in this wonderful
thing and and and those qualifications
for those people is vast. New Mexico has
a very rural community and a lot of
those people I would say don't hold
professional licenses and so think about
who can qualify and I want I would just
like it to be opened you know between
therapists massage therapists uh anybody
pharmacists nurses doctors of course but
you know in the medical side with the
ICD10 coding that makes sense to keep it
as a medical professional in that in
that realm but once they code that, you
know, we're really transitioning that
patient to a different service and that
service really needs to be thought about
differently in a way than the medical
model. And and so with that service, you
know, we're going to be providing
something different. Um, and so those
qualifications can also include other
people. And so I want to make sure that,
you know, in Oregon, there's a vast a
variety of different backgrounds with
these people. lawyers, again, just so
many different people who don't have
professional degrees, who barely have
college, and and I want to make sure
that they're included. And so that's why
I'm here today is to make sure I
advocate for those people coming up here
and that we include a a large group of
people who are trained appropriately,
of course, you know, but once they're
trained appropriately, they will follow
under the DO and the licensing and and
that'll go the way it always has and
goes very well. And so, but let's look
at those qualifications and say, you
know, let's include these other people.
And so that's all I have to say today.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, James.
If anyone else would like to speak at
this time, please go ahead and raise
your hand on the Microsoft Teams uh
application via your computer or on the
phone. If you're some uh joining us
through voice, it's star five to raise
or lower your hand.
>> Hey Desba, I know you had a comment
earlier, but you were muted. Um did you
still want to speak? Yeah, sure. Um,
yeah, I just Well, can we can we comment
on the comments?
Um, no, I I wanted to say from the
equity access uh
spectrum, um, the things that were
Hanife was saying and Denali was saying,
especially because I also was looking at
the chat. um you know when it comes to
that practicum that's a really good idea
because and I just wanted to point this
out um we're seeing the kind of the the
practicum side of what that looks like
and again also to I think was it James
who just spoke a second ago um the and
the chat the facilitator is different in
some ways than a medical professional
which is what La Lita is also working
towards um with her program. It seems
that you know the medical professional
the western medicine side has a
different perspective and intention when
it comes to working with patients
um than would be different than say
cultural considerations for kuranderas
and um and indigenous healers. So what
does that look like when they intersect?
That would be a great place for uh
understanding what a facilitator,
someone who is sitting with a person who
is journeying. Um and that might be
completely different than having the
perspective from western medicine versus
someone who has been practicing this for
decades and has the wisdom from you know
years. Um but on the equity side you
know what does it look like to travel?
What does it look like someone from Mura
or someone from Farmington or someone
from Deming to travel to these different
sites and the cost uh that might
prohibit those things? Um
but yeah, I just well I just kind of
wanted to make a little bit of a comment
on on that. Oh, the the the practicum.
We're seeing that also with the early
childhood education and the internships
that are needed. And that's where I see
kind of like the similarities in what I
hear people are saying is that it's one
thing to have the knowledge and to do
something. It's quite different than to
actually be there sitting with someone
and following them through what they
need to have and the integration that's
necessary. So I just kind of wanted to
echo um the possible um concern that
some people might have is what does that
look like in terms of training? What
does that look like when it comes to
like Larry's committee like end of care?
um sitting with someone who is dying is
is a completely different thing than
sitting to some some degree than someone
who might be having um post-traumatic
stress disorder from um being a war
veteran. And so I just kind of wanted to
point that out.
>> Yeah. Well, thank you so much. I really
appreciate that that insight. Um, and I
think I gave the equity committee so
broad of jurisdiction because it's it's
so important that this program doesn't
become a big filter. And what I mean by
that is is when we're requiring more of
people, we're requiring them to travel.
We're requiring them to um we're adding
barriers to care. Then we're not no
longer saying, "Oh, is this patient best
for psilocybin?" are saying, "Does this
patient have a bed a good enough job and
a flexible enough job where they can
travel? Do they have um the ability to
travel, a mechanism, a mode of
transportation? How far are they
traveling? What's the cost of gas to get
there and things like that?" So I I
definitely see your point that equity is
so incredibly important because I the
last thing I want is this program to
just turn into another instance of where
you know um urban areas get preferential
treatment. I think we have to very much
consider how much it costs each person
to make it to the um administration
session, how much it costs each person
to um take off that time from work, um
if we're able to get insurance coverage
and that kind of thing. Um or education
we need to provide. Like that's the
where I kind of stand on those issues,
but I really appreciate them. Um
Lawrence, you had a
You're muted.
>> Yeah, thank you. I I had a couple of
comments just on the the training part.
Um I'd encourage us to to think about
teams a team's approach here. I mean,
that's a lot of how we're doing other
forms of health care. And I mean the
idea that you know that there's somebody
has some a level of training that's
sitting with people makes this really
accessible but that there's somebody
else in the team that made that
diagnosis um um is helpful as well. And
and one could actually have somebody
who's a therapist that's not there on
site that is available because there are
people that will come out of the
psilocybin session. Most of the time
people come out well occasionally people
come out with more existential paranoid
sort of issues. So think of it as like a
team offering. That is one thing. Um the
other is to look a little bit about the
indications and that we may need
different training plans for different
ones. Um like in Colorado they have you
know it's certain diagnosis that you
know it kind of escalates to getting
some um uh some consultation or someone
else involved. You know just just to
share one one sort of quick example. Um
PTSD can be very variable. If people
have complex PTSD and they're having
their first psilocybin session, that's
that's a that's a situation where
honestly many of the people I know who
offer psychedelic um therapy in other
states are are reticent there without
having somebody who has experienced that
level of trauma. So think about teams,
think about different diagnoses and
different teams for those is is my
thoughts.
>> Yeah. And thank you so much, Larry. Um,
and to add on top of that, one of the
things I've considered for for who our
provider or uh facilitator should be,
I've definitely considered having them
be nurses. The reason why is that nurses
are already trained to assess. They are
trained to um help with people, to have
social communication. Um, and so that
assessment part though is really
important to me because psilocybin can
have um impacts on your cardiovascular
system. So if we can have someone there
to just be able to say even if it's not
a a psychiatric distortion caused by the
psilocybin, maybe it's a cardiovascular
incident, maybe it's a um mental health
incident or other things like that where
it may be beneficial to have a member of
the healthcare team, maybe not a doctor,
maybe not um you know someone people
trust less because there is a deep found
trust doctors in our system, but that's
neither here nor there. Um, so I just
wanted to talk about, you know, kind of
that point and I will go ahead and turn
over to Brenda.
>> I appreciate everybody's comment here
because this is the warm-up for the
education and training. Absolutely. I'm
I'm I'm really loving seeing everybody
contribute to everything that's going on
here right now because it's going to to
actually uh you know speed up things for
the for the meeting for education. But
going back to what uh Despa was saying,
the intersection, this is really
important. um you know people who are
trained traditionally and people who are
trained in western modalities
what that's going to look like and how
are we going to build together and like
Larry was saying as a team um there may
be uh a little bit of a hybrid here that
we can start to work on together and
work on something here with training and
with a practicum or internship or
however that's going to look like.
um and start to um build on this as um
prior to the meeting. So, I like this.
Everybody's got their thinking caps on
that are commenting on what training is
going to be and what it's going to look
like. So, um thank you everybody for
contributing.
>> Yes, thank you. And I will turn back to
Adrian to uh for public comment.
>> Thank you. Uh, next up is James Hosobo.
James, I've enabled your microphone
credentials. Can you please unmute
yourself?
>> Yeah. Can you hear me? Okay.
>> Yes. Wonderful. Well, good morning
everybody and this is an absolutely
wonderful birthday present to be here
with you all today. Um, one point that I
would really like to recommend to the
board in regards to protect patient
safety and maintain public trust is to
implement a structured framework for
monitoring facilitators that are
providing the psychotherapy. I think
this would literally include um
credentiing, background verification,
and participating in a centralized
facilitator registry. I think that this
is really important to make sure that
there are boundaries, nonviolations,
and um any
ethical conduct that needs to be
surveillanced. Um I know that, you know,
human beings, we're all not perfect, and
nefarious behaviors may arise and I
believe that my recommendation for the
facilitator registry might uh help
mitigate and help bring uh harm
reduction into this uh realm. So, thank
you very much for listening to what I
have to say and I look forward to the
next meeting.
>> Thank you, James.
Next up is Katherine. Katherine, I've
enabled your microphone credentials.
Will you go ahead and please unmute
yourself?
>> Good morning, everybody. Uh, thank you
again for uh everybody's time and effort
in these um meetings. This is a very
important thing we're doing here and I
just want to say thank you to everybody.
Um, something I wanted to just weigh in
on Ian based on what you were sharing.
I've been doing this work for about four
years now and what I will tell you that
has been extremely important and
valuable is making sure that people
anybody that like I use an assessment
but anytime anything is like you know uh
flagged like severe cardiovascular
issues um epilepsy unmanaged diabetes I
do require that they actually um you
know see a medical provider to get that
further assessment. So, I almost think
it might be good um to have two levels
of assessment. There's the preliminary
assessment and then if a medical
assessment is needed, I do think that
that's something that we may want to
very much consider. Um I I liked your
idea of including nurses, but I actually
think there needs to be a step to make
sure that the liability isn't and the
onus isn't on the facilitators who don't
have medical backgrounds. Um, I actually
uh use the www um w.in
psychedelicction.com
when anybody's taking medications
because it is um a pharmacist uh website
that provides contraindications.
Um, I prefer as much as possible to have
backing from medical professionals that
are telling clients what is
contraindicated, what the issues are,
not coming from a licensed therapist,
which you know is is something, but it's
I don't have that background and I I
don't want um I don't want to see
guides, facilitators, um shamans,
whatever, you know, death doulas be the
ones that ultimately are responsible for
medical um care when we don't really
have that background. So, thank you very
much um for letting me speak. Have a
wonderful day everybody.
>> Yeah, and definitely I wouldn't want to
exclude therapists or anything like
that. I my goal in having a nurse was
having a nurse on facility. Um it would
just say if someone has like a serious
incident at least we have someone there
to assess and who we can say we'll get
them to the emergency room but who can
provide emergency care on route and who
can you know help out with emergency
situations. Are cardiovascular incidents
very common with psilocybin? No. But
that doesn't mean we shouldn't still
take steps to prevent an
sentinel event. Um so
just very important to me that we have
someone you know who is trained on
medical properties and things like that
just to be able to say you know is their
pulse feeling threat what did their lab
results say how are they um you know
cope how is their body working right
because we don't want to add unnecessary
stress into a situation um right like if
we're treating someone for
post-traumatic stress disorder we don't
want to give them new trauma by sending
them to the hospital um if they had you
know uncontrolled heart disease. Um so I
just it's a more about an abundance of
caution than saying each person must be
allocated a nurse and be by them the
entire time because in all fairness um
nurses are not psychiatric
professionals. They are not
psychologists. They are not therapists.
So I do believe in the importance of
integration and administration with a
licensed therapist because that that is
their specialty. But at the same time I
recognize that we may need a nurse to
say hey um this person answered this
questionnaire in this way. How are we
interpreting those results and things
like that? Uh Chris, you had a question.
Yeah, I just want to say I think having
a nurse on staff at these is going to be
very cost prohibitive for everybody and
I I think Colorado requires a BLS um for
their facilitators which I think is
would be more than sufficient given the
the high safety profile of psilocybin
and in those rare conditions I think the
the preliminary screening can mitigate
other other issues and requiring, you
know, um clearance from a doctor to
participate in some of this would be a
much better option than than having
nurses at all of these sessions. That
that seems overly abundant. And I I also
think for for uh
you know, integration and and coaching
and all that that you know that should
be broad as well. I think peer support
workers and people of all walks of life
can can help people that are especially
like them uh deal with these issues and
how to integrate them. So just thoughts.
>> Absolutely. Um but I do still stand by
the fact that the entire purpose of a
nurse is to assess. We look at what is
happening. We look at all of the details
down to if there's clubbing in the
fingers, if there is skin is dry. We are
looking at everything because we're
trying to say, is this person medically
stable? Are they um going to be okay?
Are they going to tolerate the
medications they've been prescribed? And
those kind of things um are very
important to nurses. So, I've always in
my mind when I envisioned it, not in my
mind when I envisioned it, it was a team
of therapists working in a facility.
They would have their set of patients
and above them would be a nurse who
would just be there to say if something
is going wrong, if someone starts to
feel a certain way, nauseous, if they
start to sweat, if they start to, you
know, experience signs that are
sometimes normal symptoms but can also
be indications of other issues, we can
look at that and have them properly
assessed. Um, that's it's just a safety
thing for me. It's not saying that um
that therapists can't do the job. I
believe therapists can facilitate much
better than most nurses, but um it is
about just keep being sure that all of
our patients remain safe. In terms of
cost prohibitiveness,
therapists are usually more expensive
per hour than nurses. So, it already
would be like the therapist on its own
is cost prohibitive. Adding one nurse to
a facility staff is not going to, you
know, fully derail that. But I am open
to other opinions. Uh Brenda,
>> well, um just having an overall safety
plan. Um I think if you even have a
nurse um like on the phone, you say,
"Hey, uh this this um patient is uh
really having a hard time breathing. Uh
something's going on." because people um
sometimes things happen uh and they've
never had those symptoms before. So
having a nurse just on on the phone, you
know, you could be in a rural area and
also uh know how far the the hospital is
or emergency. Um having, you know, all
of that in place so that when there's an
emergency that arises,
you know, you're on it. you're you're
getting uh another opinion. Um and so
have that all set set up so prior to any
sessions that are happening with
psilocybin it's all set and so that just
gives another layer of safety.
>> I would concur with Brenda on that. That
sounds like a great idea. Even if the
nurse was just on call, I hadn't
considered it. But it is another way we
could prov pass along symptoms and see
if something is an emergency case and
get them adequate care if needed. So I I
100% support what Brenda was saying. Uh
Desba
>> just really quickly um yeah I you know
if this is a discussion because that
does have an equity access you know for
role when we're talking about the
teleaalth we were talking about
tellaalth you know uh possibly for um
preession then during the session if
there is a teleaalth person available
kind of on call similar to if not
everybody you know uh I think it was it
um I have friends who are um deaf, you
know, they need a call. They have
someone who's available to help them
facilitate the phone call or anything
else, but it doesn't mean that they have
to always be, you know, on site. But
especially for those rural areas, that's
where the intersection of equity access
could also, you know, play a part um
with our regulations.
>> And Alana,
>> yeah, hi. I'm just a little um can I get
a little bit of a uh understanding of
like kind of procedurally cuz we're
we're in public comment now. So are we
having discussions or making decisions
cuz I was kind of
>> holding for other times to have that
kind of conversation and discussion
>> is that do we do do we do I mean just
I'm I in these advisory boards we almost
never respond to public comment. we
receive public comment then we have
other ex times when we um you know
discuss as a board. So I just kind of
wanted to um
public comment period is going to be
like an official rule making procedure.
We are just trying to hear from the
people of New Mexico. We're trying to
let them hear what we are thinking on
this issue. That way when they come to
committee and we are um ready to work
they can say okay well they've already
heard this idea or that idea or some
other things and maybe can um begin to
bridge but it right now is not an
official rulem capacity. We kind of had
a little bit of extra time in between
people um who were raising their hands.
Um so we just uh had a little bit of
discussion. Nothing set in stone right
now.
>> Okay. I I mean I would just posit that
we if we get a list of people if we're
like and done there's nobody else but
usually we have like kind of a the way
I've I've been in these before is an a
list that we know ahead of time these
people are giving public comment we
wouldn't open it up for like any kind of
free discussion unless we were at the
end of it. I just want to make sure
everyone has a has a chance to make
their public comments.
>> So um I had not been given a list of the
who had requested to speak for public
comment. I had just been going off of
who was raising their hands. So,
whenever there was no one left raising
their hands, that's kind of what I went
to. I see James Brown is left. Um, and
since we have about 8 minutes, I'm he is
free to speak.
>> James, your microphone has been enabled.
Will you please unmute yourself
>> again? Thank you everyone. This is great
discussions. Um, one of the things I had
on public comment today was with the
with the thought behind a medical
professional, really with that RN
thought, it's a more of a medical
professional thought. I really like the
Colorado idea of, you know, um, up
stepping it up a little bit. Um, Oregon
didn't have the requirements on a
facilitator to have BLS, you know, that
basic life safety. Um, I think that's
important, too. um that brings that RN
discussion in or medical provider again
somebody that's just medically trained
um and and basic stuff in this stuff
when we're in our when our experiences
when we're in our sessions with our
clients you know um that pre-screening
is very important you know preparation's
huge in this and so as you prepare and
you see those things and you see those
challenges that might come up during
their session you know you have to make
arrangements and I like that that maybe
you have that hotline or on call ability
of an RN or medical professional
being that that person who is who can
make that call. Um and then and then
it's up to the facilitator trained with
the individual. Again, I want to focus
this back. We keep focusing not on
individual patients. The patients
experience is very important here and
what they grow and experience and
overcome. And so with that safety plan,
it's huge. And so that'll that'll come
into the fact here is like what have
other states done with their safety
plans? Let's look at that. Um and then
that individual um personal you know
once we once we ICD9 code them you know
then they get turned over to the
psilocybin program and then then once
that individual is turned over again you
know we got to take care of them through
safety and that individual plan of
safety is very important here and that
includes the pre-screening and whether
you're doing medication pre-screening or
polyarm pharmacy or poly substance or
whatever else you're looking at their
health conditions. Um, you know, it's
important to have those people and
resources available for those patients
to make the call individually. So again,
this isn't a a one and all, one and
done. We need to look at individuals
here and think about that too when we
make these decisions. This is going to
be individually based on their growth so
that they can overcome these things.
Thank you so much.
>> Thank you, James.
Next up is Gregory Evans. Gregory, I've
enabled your microphone credentials.
Will you please unmute yourself?
>> I'm here. I'm going to keep it to 90
seconds.
I have uh comment kind of directed at
the community that is supporting uh the
the community participation here today
and moving forward and what we can do to
be as supportive to the board because I
believe that all of us are here to
support the advisory board in their
capacity to put these recommendations
together and then move them
This is a political process.
Um, I just want to remind everybody that
we need to know which room we are in and
what that room needs at that time.
There's a lot of really valuable
discussion here on very specific topics
that I would encourage you to write
those thoughts down, show up to the
appropriate meeting and make sure that
those thoughts are put into the correct
place where they can be more effective
rather than public comment in this
space. I think that we have a process to
collect some of those thoughts, but we
don't want to lose these thoughts and
this is not the space to collect them.
Um, outside of that, just great job,
Ian. Keep doing you. Um, thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. At this time, no one else has
their hand raised for any additional
comment.
All right, seeing as there is no um
additional comment, we reviewed the
summaries from the committees an update
from the program and just generally
discussed and heard public comment.
Other than that, I say we move to
ajourn.
>> This is Dan. I'll make that motion.
>> A second.
Second it.
>> All right. Are there any objections to
the motion to adjurnn?
>> Without objection, the motion passes and
the meeting is adjourned. I thank you
guys all so much for coming and have a
wonderful rest of your January.
>> Thank you everyone.